《疯狂的麦克斯》
（正义厅）
（离现今不久后的未来…）
这是例行追缉
This is a routine pursuit.
基地回复 这是例行追缉 代码44
Main Force repeats, this is a routine pursuit. Code 44.
告诉他们 我们需要支援
Listen, you tell them we need some help.
这应该是公开代码的闪电行动 你是知道的
This should be an open-code blitz, and you know it.
你们已有足够信息
You have your information.
拜托 亲爱的 这是条大鱼
Come on, sweetheart, this one's a heavyweight!
基地回复 你们已掌握信息
Main Force repeats, you have your information.
这是例行追缉 请向大巴普通报
This is a routine pursuit. Please report to Big Bopper.
三月兔呼叫大巴普 请求援助 代码3 红色警报
March Hare to Big Bopper. Assist on Code 3 red alert.
三月 兔呼叫大巴普…
March Hare to Big Bopper. March Hare to Big Bopper.
大巴普 收到了 三月兔 怎么回事？
Big Bopper. Gotcha, Hare. What's going down?
- 我们发现一个警察杀手 - 没开玩笑吧
- We've got a cop-killer. - You're kidding!
我警告你了 塞斯 这是违抗命令
Be warned, Sarse, this is non-compliance.
基地不会容忍这样的行为
The Main Force will not tolerate such action.
这不是3号红色警报 这场追缉被指定为代码44
This is not a Code 3 red alert. This pursuit is designated a standard Code 44.
请不要向其他代码作出回应
Please respond only to that code.
代码44说明不必封锁道路
Code 44 indicates no requirement for a blockade.
一辆追缉专用车被偷了
A Pursuit Special has been stolen.
市府大队长费贾麦卡菲 比你还讨厌这种事
Hall Captain Fifi Macaffee does not like this any more than you.
然而我们不能在领土方面妥协
However, we must not compromise territorial range.
记住 唯有遵循指示
Remember that only by following instructions…
我们才有希望维持一个规范的公路秩序
…can we hope to maintain a successful highway program.
啊 天啊
Ah, Jesus!
三月兔呼叫大巴普 我们三分钟后到路口
March Hare to Big Bopper. We're three minutes off the intersection.
- 你们赶得到吗？- 我们能赶到 让开
- Reckon you can make it? - We'll make it! Move over!
- 罗普 - 由我开车
- Roop! - I'm driving!
这次不行 我才是这次行动的受指派者
Not this again! I've been assigned!
等一下 应该由我开车才对
Wait a second, you son of a bitch. I'm supposed to drive this heap!
你才给我等等 我已经忍无可忍了
Where do you get off, huh? Where do you get off?
塞斯 这家伙长什么模样？
Hey, Sarse, what's the form on this guy?
一个古怪的机车骑士
A weirdo bike jockey.
几小时前在太阳城被发现 他像疯了一样
A few hours ago, down in Sun City, he goes berserk.
挣脕拘捕 杀了个年轻员警 开着追缉专用车逃走了
Breaks custody, wastes a rookie and takes off in a Pursuit Special.
我们一直在追他
We've been on him ever since.
这人发疯了 罗普
This one's as flaky as they come, Roop.
我看过那种风格 严重精神病患
I've seen the style before. It's terminal psychotic.
他驾驶什么车？
What's he driving?
这才是最要命的 我们的V8之一
That's what hurts. It's one of our V8s.
使用甲烷的追缉专用车 性能很强
Pursuit Special on methane. Super hot!
我们离无政府之路只有半里路
Okay, we're about half a mile off Anarchy Road.
你随时会看到他
You'll see him any minute now.
我要将他开肠剖肚 给他好看
Rip the guts out of him! Give it to me, Jesus!
看到他没？
See him yet?
看到了
Got it!
- 我要轰掉他 - 可恶
- I'm gonna blow him away! - Goddamn him!
我要撞死他
I'm gonna ram him!
远离乘客座位的门
Move away from the passenger door.
我要撞死他
I'm gonna ram him!
老兄 你们还好吗？
Hey, fellas, you okay?
收到请回答 大巴普 收到请回答 你们还好吗？
Acknowledge, Big Bopper. Acknowledge, are you okay?
罗普？查理？
Roop? Charlie?
你们看到我没 斩脚趾
Do you see me, Toecutter?
看到我的厉害没？
Do you see me, man?
继续追… 我们没事
Keep going. Keep going, we're okay.
收到 我们继续去追
We got you, we're going.
我生来手握方向盘
Born with a steering wheel in his hand…
脚踩油门
…and lead in his foot.
我是夜骑士
I am the Nightrider…
以吓死人的速度狂飘
…cruising at the speed of fright!
我是夜骑士 我勇往直前
I am the Nightrider, and I ain't never coming back!
我是喷射燃油的自杀机器
I'm a fuel-injected suicide machine!
听见了么 你们这帮猪脑子 听见了么？
Do you hear me, pigs? Do you hear me, Bronze pigs? Do you hear me, Bronze?
我想我们还能动
I think we're still mobile.
天杀的 滚过去
For Christ's sake, shove over!
你又在出口成脏了
You're blaspheming again.
我不跟没素质的人合作
I don't have to work with a blasphemer.
你们跟丢了 猪脑子 嘿 大个子 我是夜骑士
Well, you missed us, pig! Hey, big brother, this is The Nightrider…
大巴普呼叫三月兔 我们还在追 好吗？
Big Bopper to March Hare. We're still in the game, okay?
了解
Understand this.
那个人渣和他的小贱人
That Scag and his floozie…
他们都死定了
…they're gonna die!
代码44 标准追缉 请回应
Code 44, standard pursuit. Please respond.
基地巡逻队呼叫小鹅一号
MFP to Gosling One.
（基地巡逻队）
基地呼叫小鹅一号
Come on, Goose, where are you?
那就像慢动作
It was like slow motion.
他从座位上弹起来 撞破挡风玻璃
He leaves his seat and goes through the windshield…
直接撞上树 对吧？
…headfirst straight into the tree, right…
然后从挡风玻璃弹回去
…and then bounces back through the windshield.
等我们来到他那里时 他只是坐在那里
And by the time we got to him, he was just sitting there…
脸皮都给撕烂了 还想嚷嚷
…trying to scream with his face ripped off.
怎么回事？
What's the matter?
我不饿
Not hungry anymore.
拿过来 我告诉你…
Give it here. I'll tell you what…
天啊 他们朝人群冲过去了
Christ, they're heading for population!
我听说你跟强纳森 到底是怎么了
Now, what's this I hear about you and Jonathan?
- 强纳森怎样？- 有人两晚前看到你跟他出去
- What about him? - You were seen with him two nights ago.
那又怎样？
So what?
朝这方向
It's, um, this way.
他挂了
He's gone.
混蛋
Bastard!
该死
Oh, shit!
你这次真的死定了 他刚才是开了转弯灯的
You're really gonna get it this time. He had his indicator on.
闭嘴
Shut up!
不 你不能再开了 别上路
No, no, you're not going on. Stay off the road!
我当然要开 闭嘴
Of course, I'm going on. Shut up!
你已经威胁到人民群众的生命安全
People's lives are in peril!
你知道不知道你在干嘛 你疯了吗？
What are you doing? You gone nuts?
我要逮到他
Do I have him?
别挡在路上
Stay off the road!
- 我发现他了 闭嘴… - 继续盯着他
- I got him! Shut up! - Stay on him!
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
小心
Watch out!
- 好惊险 - 哈哈
- Great! Down in one. - Ha-ha-ha!
我准备好了
I am ready.
我完全准备好了
I am ready for your best.
天啊 发生什么事？
Oh, my God, what happened?
我不知道 我也是刚到这儿
I don't know, man. I just got here myself.
基地巡逻队
Main Force Patrol…
我们玩完了
…we're out of the game…
无法继续追缉
…unable to continue pursuit.
你们最好派运肉卡车来
You'd better send a meat truck.
查理伤得很严重
Charlie's been hurt bad in the throat.
麦克斯？
Hey, Max?
收到吗 麦克斯？
Can you hear me, Max?
请说
Go ahead.
我们完全乱成一团
We are 100 percent snafued.
你还好吗？
You okay, Goose?
到热带地区过一年 什么都能好转
Nothing a year in the tropics wouldn't fix!
损坏严重吗？
Much damage?
你应该来看看情况 条子
You should see the damage, Bronze! Huh?
金属损坏
Metal damage…
脑部损坏 你在听吗 条子？
…brain damage, huh? You listening, Bronze?
我是夜骑士
I am the Nightrider!
我是喷射燃油的自杀机器
I'm a fuel-injected suicide machine.
我又摇又滚 完全失控
I am a rocker! I am a roller! I am an out-of-controller!
我是夜骑士 宝贝
I am a Nightrider, baby…
我和我的马马杜 一往无前 永不言败
…and it's me and my Marmaduke, and we ain't never coming back.
（拦截车）
斩脚趾
The Toecutter…
他知道我是谁
…he knows who I am.
我是夜骑士
I am the Nightrider!
我是救世主 强大的复仇之手
I am the chosen one, the mighty hand of vengeance…
降临世界 打击那些不值得上路的人
…sent down to strike the unroadworthy! Ha-ha-ha!
我比滚动的骰子更火热
I'm hotter than a rolling dice.
上前来 老兄
Step right up, chum…
看那小子
…and watch the kid…
开出通往自由的一条橡胶大道
…lay down a rubber road, right to freedom!
哪里不对劲？宝贝 哪里不对劲？
What's wrong? Baby, what's wrong?
告诉我怎么了
Tell me what's wrong!
完蛋了…
It's going.
什么都不剩 完蛋了
There'll be nothing left. It's all gone.
停车
Stop! Stop!
感觉真好
Ah, that feels good.
过了三天 那感觉真好
After three days that feels so good.
今天早上我一记右钩拳打在他脸上
I got a right hook in the mouth this morning.
- 小不点？- 嗯
- Sprog? - Mm.
我告诉他无论什么时候都要注意防左边
I told him to always lead with his left.
我想我们的手中都有怪物附体
You know, I think we've got a monster on our hands.
是啊 都是跟他老爹学的
Yeah, takes after his old man.
- 什么？- 怪物
- What's that? - Monster!
蒙塔赞诺 他自称夜骑士
Montazano, who called himself the Nightrider…
从拘留所劫持一辆警车后逃跑
…had broken from custody and escaped to the police vehicle.
- 你又上新闻了 - 嗯
- You made the news again. Hm. - Mm.
他是谁？
Who was he?
不知道
I don't know.
我猜是另一个光荣骑士
Just another glory roader, I guess.
洁西 我告诉过你
Jessie, I told you.
大鹅想要我早点到
The Goose wants me there early.
他没说是为了什么
What for, he didn't say.
你知道大鹅这人
You know the Goose.
咖啡煮好了
Coffee's ready.
我没在生闷气
I'm not grumpy.
给我出去
Get out of here.
好
0kay.
我该走了
I gotta go.
嘿
Hey!
什么意思？
What's that?
为你痴狂
Crazy about you.
对于肇事者的处罚
Penalties against pirate towing-operators…
将会在下一季加强
…will be stiffened considerably in the next quarter.
对肇事者拘留将会改为直接没收其装备
Driver detention will be replaced by rig confiscation.
在此新法令下的二次犯
Second offenders under the new decree…
将与州汽车主管单位见面
…will be met by state appropriation of the unauthorized vehicles.
备忘录第三条
Memorandum Three:
最近在《人民公报》报导的事件
The incidents have been reported recently in the People's Gazette.
在基地成员之间 将不允许出现燃料买卖现象
There is to be no dealing in petroleum by members of the Main Force.
备忘录第七条
Memorandum Seven:
市府大队长们要求追缉警员
The Captains of the Hall have asked that pursuit officers…
在基地追缉队时 避免使用「条子」这样的俚语
…refrain from using the slang "Bronze" for the Main Force Patrol.
这一词有不敬意味
The word is considered disrespectful…
应主动劝阻市民使用它
…and citizens should actively be discouraged from its use.
你把那家伙的锐气杀光了 巴瑞
Kick it in the guts, Barry.
它是剩下的最后一辆V8
She's the last of the V8s.
你一定会爱死这辆 她实在是太棒了
You can shut the gate on this one. It's the Duck's guts.
是啊 她是我们最后一辆V8了
Yeah, she's the last of the V8s.
硝化甘油动力
Sucks nitro.
四向变速 双重顶置凸轮
Phase 4, head, twin overhead cam.
给他说说这个蜗轮 600匹马力
Tell him about the Blower. Six hundred horsepower.
它是会唱歌的霸王 这车生来就要奔驰
The Blower! The Blower, man!
- 他被迷住 了 - 他喜欢它
- He's in a coma, man! - He loves it.
好
0kay.
你们是怎么组装出来的？
How the hell did you get all this together?
就像你看见的一样 麦克斯 你知道的
It just happened, Max, you know?
这里凑一凑 那里拼一拼
A piece from here and a piece from there.
- 这么简单？- 对
- So easy? - Yeah.
得了 麦克斯 你看过车 听过车发动 还要问问题？
Come on, Max. You've seen it, you've heard it, and you're still asking questions?
武士码1 多重致命进度46…
Code Samurai 1, progress 46 on multiple fatal. Code Samurai 1.
我们何时去兜风？
When do we go for a ride?
野兽
Animal!
我想我们找到他了
I think we've got him.
我希望是
I hope so.
对 我们找到他了
Yeah, we've got him.
你的第一追击手想不干了…
Your top pursuit man wants to quit the road…
我们得拿甜头来引诱他回来？
…and we have to seduce him with candy?
人们对英雄己不抱信心了
People don't believe in heroes anymore.
我知道 麦卡菲 你想把英雄还给他们
I know, Macaffee. You want to give them back their heroes.
你这招对我不再管用
You will not try this one on me again.
我不喜欢浪费钱
I do not enjoy wasting money.
再见
Goodbye…
祝你好运
…and good luck!
谢了 拉巴吐什
Thanks, Labatouche…
你真是个好人
…you're a real human being.
闭嘴 给我滚开
Shut up! Get out of here!
给我滚开
Get out of my way!
那个老机器今晚又开工了吧
The old meat grinder's humming tonight, eh?
对 麦克斯刚搞定一对疯子
Yeah, Max took out a couple of crazies just now, that's all.
闭嘴行不行？
Hey, shut up!
麦克斯 又有了一次光辉记录了吧 你吃过没？
Hey, Max, another one for your books, eh? You eaten yet?
不 还没 我待会再买点束西
No, not yet. I'll pick up something later.
你前几天去追缉的3号状况
Hey, that, urn, Code 3 you ran down a few days ago.
- 夜骑士？- 夜骑士 对
- The Nightrider? - The Nightrider, yeah.
- 有问题 - 什么问题？
- Got a problem. - What's that?
他的朋友 听说他们想出动对付你
Well, his friends. Word is they're out to get you.
- 机车骑士？- 对 游手好闲的垃圾
- Scoot jockeys? - Yeah, nomad trash.
我会加在我的恐吓名单里
Hmm. Well, I'll add it to my threat collection.
好小子 麦克斯 你是好小子
Ha, ha. Good boy, Max. You're a good boy.
嘿 来吧
Hey, come on.
午安
Good afternoon.
我来这里见一位朋友 他坐火车来
We're here to meet a friend. Coming on the train.
没人下火车 只有几箱束西和…
Nothing coming on the train except a couple of crates and a, heh…
一具棺材
…coffin.
是我们的朋友
Our friend.
你们要去找经手人 签署文件
You'll have to see the agent and sign the papers.
我们在哪能找到…
Where do we find…
这个代理人
…this agent?
等着
Wait.
里面应该是你们的朋友
That must be your friend over there.
别让他太嚣张了
Didn't leave much of him.
该把他的心挖出来，对吧
Must have cut his heart out, huh?
对 我就这个意思
Yeah. That's what I meant.
可怜的家伙
Poor bastard.
夜骑士
The Nightrider…
他叫这名字
…that is his name.
夜骑士
The Nightrider.
记住他的名字…
Remember him…
当你仰望夜空的时候
…when you look at the night sky.
我会的
I will.
把你的帽子摘下来
Take your hat off.
全听你的话
Anything you say.
全听我的话
Anything I say.
你怎么能保持如此的冷静
What a wonderful philosophy you have.
把他带走
Take him away.
布巴 强尼
Bubba.Johnny.
噢
Oh!
- 你逼我 我就干掉你 - 是吗？谁说的？
- Push me, shove you! - Oh, yeah? Says who?
你逼我 我就干掉你
Push me, shove you, push me, shove you, push me, shove you!
加油 夜骑士
Come on! Nightrider!
夜骑士
Nightrider!
别担心
Don't worry.
总之 我叫吉姆大鹅
Anyway, my name is Jim Goose.
这里是洛卡谭斯基
Rockatansky, here.
威耶路撒冷有案件发生
We have incident at Wee Jerusalem.
游荡的机车骑士 大麻烦
Nomad bikers, bulk trouble.
好 我们去处理 我们走
Okay, we're on it. We're going.
大鹅 我们走
Goose, let's go.
该走了 抱歉
So long. Sorry, we gotta go.
这是什么？
What's this?
这是不必坐牢的兔死金牌
It's a get-out-of-jail-free card.
- 有其他细节吗？- 没有
- Any more details? - No.
好 我们走了
Okay, we're going.
- 麦克斯 看到没？- 有
- Max, see what I see? - Yeah.
嘿 老兄 站住
Hey, fella, stop!
嘿 老兄
Hey, fella!
哈
Ah.
嘿 老兄 站住
Hey, fella, stop!
真是大笨蛋
What a turkey!
老兄 你就是个笨蛋 你知道吗？
Hey, fella, you're a turkey, you know that?
我们回来再收拾他 前面有大事要办
We'll come back for him later. There's more up ahead.
夜骑士
Nightrider.
看看她
See to her.
条子
Bronze!
他们会逮到你的
Gonna get you!
好了
0kay.
没事的 没人会伤害你
It's all right. No one's gonna hurt you.
没事的
It's all right.
这个人是个疯子
This one's whacked out of his skull.
完全疯了
Whacked right out of his skull, man!
他不会回来了
He ain't never coming back. Whoo!
没事了…
It's all right.
已经没事了
我现在会放掉绳子
I'm gonna let this go now.
我知道你很害怕 女孩
I know you're a frightened girl…
但是再也不会有人伤害你了
…but no one's gonna hurt you anymore.
我叫吉姆大鹅 现在一切都没事了
My name's Jim Goose, and everything's gonna be all right.
费费希望太阳城的事件不会再发生了
Fifi wants no recurrence of the Sun City incident.
警告人们别挡路 用你的警笛
Warn people off the roads. Use your sirens.
夜骑士
The Nightrider!
- 吉姆 - 怎样？
- Hey, Jimbo. - Yeah?
- 记得3号代码吗？- 当然记得
- Remember that Code 3? - Yeah, sure.
当你看着夜空时要想…
Remember him when you look up!
当你…
When you look…
夜骑士
Nightrider!
不得了
Well, Well, Well!
强尼小子又来了
Johnny the Boy is still at the wreck.
这是个教训
Stoned again.
他从来不知道吸取教训
He's never gonna learn.
但我们要好好教训他 布巴
But we are going to teach him, Bubba.
你要回去找他
You are going back for him.
才不要 我不去 不去
No way! Not me, not for him!
但这不是为了他
But it's not for him.
是为了我 布巴
It's for me, Bubba.
你在浪费时间 那废物什么都不是
You're wasting your time! The Scag don't rate!
他跟夜骑士比起来不算什么
He's nothing like the Nightrider!
基地巡逻队 代码1
MFP Code 1.
麦卡菲大队长率领车队 正从法院前往正义厅
Captain Macaffee in convoy from the court house to the Halls of Justice.
先生
Hey, mister!
那辆车怎么了？
What happened to the car?
你认为发生了什么事？
What do you think happened?
看起来像被嚼过又吐出来
Looks like it was chewed up and spat out.
也许那是焦虑造成的结果
Perhaps it was the result of anxiety.
嘿 罗普
Hey, Roop.
留在这里
Stay here, man.
我想他们在外面
I think they're out there.
慢慢来 查理 我们时间多得很
Take your time, Charlie. We got plenty of it.
我看得到拦截车
I can see the Interceptor.
你觉得呢 人渣？
What do you say, Scag?
没别的地方去了吗？
Got no place special to go, huh?
我们最好给他准备一下
We'd better prep him.
人渣 你带了牙刷来？
Scag, did you bring your toothbrush?
- 你必须帮大鹅代班 - 为什么？
- You'll have to sit on the Goose. - Why?
- 不必多问 - 该死
- No contest. - Damn!
老费 怎么了？
Hey, Fif! What's going on?
- 发生什么事？- 放他走
- What happened? - Let him go.
他说 「放他走」 是什么意思？这是谁？
What's he mean, "Let him go"? Who's this?
- 别插手 - 怎么回事？
- Keep out of this. - What's going on?
没人出现 好吗？
No one showed, okay?
算了 查理 放他走
Forget it, Charlie. Just let him go.
没有人指认 没有人
No one showed. No one.
什么意思 「没人指认」？
What's he mean, "No one showed"?
他们没有指认罪犯
They didn't show.
没有人 阿飞没有指认犯罪
Nobody! The punks didn't show.
那个女孩没有 整个镇上的人都没有
The girl didn't show, the townspeople didn't show.
没有人指认罪犯
Nobody showed!
- 我们被耍了 - 别碰我
- We're screwed! - Don't touch me!
你说没有人来指认是什么意思？你去了哪里？
What do you mean, "No one showed"? Where were you, man?
意思是 老家伙 你的案子不成立 别多问
It means, old man, you haven't got a case. No contest.
天啊 你不会这样让他走人吧 费费？
Jesus Christ! You're not gonna let him walk out the door, Fifi?
你只能这么做
That's exactly what you'll do!
- 闭嘴 - 继续 查理
- Shut up, Ralphie! - Keep going, Charlie! Keep going!
嘿 条子 看看你
Hey, Bronze, look at you…
又聋又哑的废物
…a cripple and a mute!
他唱歌 我跳踢踏舞
He sings, and I tap-dance!
你知道你是什么人 你是…
Hey, you know what you are? You are, you're a…
法院会知道这一切的
The courts will hear about this, I promise you!
我向你保证
The courts will hear about this disgrace!
- 这个人令人反感到作呕 - 少挡路
- This man is grossly offensive! - Out of my way!
把他赶出去 麦克斯
Get him out of here, Max!
- 我能使这个案子成立 - 我们不可能对一种抱怨立案的
- I can make a case of it! - No one filed a complaint!
你看见他怎么对待那女孩的了
You saw what they did to that girl!
老天帮忙 她像机车一样被人骑
For God's sake, she was the town pump!
他是我的犯人 我不让他走出这扇门
He's my prisoner, and he's not walking out that door!
把他给我弄出去
Get him out of here!
这个人是谁？
Who is this guy?
大鹅 冷静一点
Goose, settle down, boy.
来吧 小子
Come on, boy.
看 他们在嘲笑我们
Look, they're laughing at us!
你们看不出他们在嘲笑我们？我不相信
Can't you see they're laughing at us? I don't believe this!
待会儿见 大鹅 真是我的荣幸
See you later, Goose. It's been a pleasure.
上车 回家 我们不需要你在这里出现
Get in the car, go home. We don't want you around here.
大鹅
Hey, Goose!
你对此无能为力
You can't do anything about it!
我们知道你是谁 条子
We know who you are, Bronze!
咱们公路上见 垃圾
We'll see you on the road, Scag!
公路上见 就像夜骑士的下场
See you on the road, like we saw the Nightrider!
我们记得夜骑士 也知道你是谁
We remember the Nightrider, and we know who you are!
好
0kay.
只要所有文书处理干净 你们就可以为所欲为了
So long as the paperwork is clean, you boys can do what you like out there.
他来了 这个骚狐狸
Here he is, the walking armpit! Ha-ha-ha!
我的肚子里有团火 只有她这女人能平息
There's a fire in my belly, and she's the woman to put it out.
少碰她 禽兽 这天使是我的
Off, brute, this angel's hot in the tubes for me!
耶 哈哈
Yee-ha!
我欲火焚身…
I'm on fire!
装疯卖傻是小孩的把戏
Joviality is a game of children.
她是我的 我这双手应该去当外科医生
She's mine. I should have been a surgeon with these hands.
酒鬼 滚出去
Mudguts, get out of there!
康迪里尼 把她靠在柱子上
Cundalini, put her against the post.
我们有麻烦了
We have a problem here.
她可不想表面看起来那么安全
She is not what she seems.
布巴赞内提有可靠消息
Bubba Zanetti has it on good authority…
是条子送她来的 一肚子坏水
…she's sent by the Bronze, full of treachery.
条子夺走我们的自尊
The Bronze kill our pride.
假如想干掉条子 就必须做大一点
If you're going to waste the Bronze, you gotta do it big!
你没那种格调 是不是 屎蛋？
You just don't have the style, do you, chicken shit?
为了一个假人下水
Goes to water on a dummy.
没问题的 你会有机会的
It's all right, you'll get your chance!
你会有机会的
You'll get your chance.
没关系 没事…
It's all right. Hm? It's okay.
没事的
It's okay.
只要记住…
Just remember…
永永远远的
…to keep your sweet…
闭上你的小嘴
…sweet mouth shut!
（蜜糖镇酒店）
噢
Whoo!
小鹅一号 执行代码3
Gosling One. Code 3 in progress.
我们得到一起违反禁宵令的举报
We have a curfew violation.
∮ 先生 请告诉我路在何方 ∮
∮ Mister, won't you show the way? ∮
∮ 我想要躲开 ∮
∮ Tryin' to get around ∮
∮ 只有一个理由让我活着 ∮
∮ Only one thought left Makes me come alive ∮
∮ 就是你我相依 ∮
∮ And that is you and me side by side ∮
∮ 速度已经爆表 ∮
∮ On the licorice ride ∮
∮ 飞车党让我从梦里醒来 ∮
∮ Motorbikes and leather men Take me to the edge of the dream ∮
∮ 紧紧抱着你 就是这种感觉 ∮
∮ Hold on tight Though, it sure feels right ∮
∮ 就这样紧紧抱着你 ∮
∮ Stick to you like a tie on a licorice ride ∮
耶 宝贝
Yeah, baby.
小队参加三天的天使巡逻
Welcome, Main Force units, to three day Angel Patrol.
很高兴你回来 大波普二号
Nice to have you back, Big Boppa Two.
基地巡逻队 收到
MFP, COPY.
嘿… 我是大鹅
Hey, hey, hey, hey, it's the Goose.
算你好运 路上出现的问题不大
You're a lucky boy. Didn't even get road rash.
嘿 密奇
Hey, Midge…
在没有看见我车毁人亡之前
…don't write off the Goose…
别小看我大鹅
…until you see the box going into the hole.
是啊 现在别撞坏我的卡车
Yeah, well don't wreck my truck now.
- 我明天开回来 - 不必急
- I'll bring it back tomorrow. - Yeah, no hurry.
你确定你还好？
Hey, sure you're all right?
好的不得了
Couldn't be righter.
吉米大鹅 活得生气盎然 只是丑毙了
Jimmy the Goose, larger than life and twice as ugly!
帮我点火 强尼
Light me, Johnny.
再点一根
Light another.
嘿…
Hey.
这是关键时刻 强尼 走过去
This is the threshold moment, Johnny. Step through.
斩脚趾 这不是我想要的结果
Toecutter, this isn't what I want.
去烧了它 烧了它 强尼 为了我
Light it! Light it, Johnny, for me.
这帮条子 总是让你失去自尊
The Bronze, they keep you from being proud.
看看他 他头上脚下 看起来是不是好呆？
Look at him. He looks silly, doesn't he, upside down?
为了自由和夜骑士动手
Do it for freedom and the Nightrider!
- 我不能 - 动手
- I can't! - Throw it!
- 不 - 你这没用的垃圾
- No! - You scum-sucking trash!
丢过去
Throw it!
（圣乔治医院）
麦克斯…
Max. Max.
麦克斯
Max.
麦克斯 嗨…
Max! Hey, Max.
里面那个…
That thing in there…
不是大鹅 绝不可能
…that's not the Goose. No way!
我饿了
I was hungry.
花生酱和蜂蜜
Peanut butter and honey.
我一直无法忘怀 洁西
I just can't get it clear in my head, Jess.
他曾经是如此充满活力的小伙子
He was so full of living, you know. He ran the franchise on it.
现在一切都不同了
Now there's nothing.
我在试着理解这件事
Here I am trying to put sense to it…
但我知道这完全没道理
…when I know there isn't any.
当我能忘怀的时就不会有事了
I'll be all right, once I get it clear in my head.
所有交通工具的修理 必须经过队长的授权
All vehicle repairs must be authorized by the Hall Captains.
警员不准直接与地下机械师接洽
Officers may not deal directly with underground mechanics.
这么做是犯法的
Doing so is an offense.
费费
Fif.
- 干嘛？- 我辞职
- What's this? - I'm through.
- 又来了？- 不 不是又来了
- Again? - No, not again.
- 我不玩了 我辞职 - 坐下
- I'm through. I'm quitting. - Sit down.
不 我不是来讨论的 我来是告诉你 我要辞职
No, I didn't come here to discuss it, I came to say it. I'm through.
一下子就好
Now just a minute!
好 大鹅死了
So the Goose bought it.
但这一向是他的生活态度
But that's the way he always came at the world.
你错了
You're wrong.
麦克斯 很久以来 都没有出现一个大家都认可的人了
Max, you'd be the first to admit it was long overdue.
好 我来告诉你怎么样
All right, I'll tell you how it is.
你很厉害 麦克斯
You're a winner, Max.
你非常棒
You're the top shelf,
我不要因为想辞职的疯狂想法 而失去你
and I won't lose you because of some crazy notion about quitting!
大家说人们对英雄已不抱信心
They say that people don't believe in heroes anymore.
去他们的
Well, damn them!
你和我 麦克斯
You and me, Max…
我们会让他们重新获得英雄
…we're gonna give them back their heroes.
老费 你真以为我信那套鬼扯？
Ah, Fif, do you really expect me to go for that crap?
你必须承认 我有一阵子听起来很吸引人吧？
You gotta admit, I sounded good there for a minute, eh?
再见 费费
Bye, Fifi.
拜托 你要我求你？
Hey, come on, do you want me to beg?
你要我跪下来痛哭？
Do you want me on my knees crying?
- 哈 - 一下子就好
- Ha, ha. - Now just a minute…
给我一个理由
Give me a reason.
- 我很害怕 老费 - 呃
- I'm scared, Fif. - Ugh.
知道原因吗？外界像是老鼠耍马戏
Do you know why? It's that rat circus out there.
我开始乐在其中了
I'm beginning to enjoy it.
你什么意思 滑稽表演节？
What is this, funny week?
听着 如果在公路上再呆下去 我就会成为他们其中一分子
Any longer out on that road, and I'm one of them, you know?
一个超级疯子
A terminal crazy.
只不过我有警徽说我是好人
Only, I've got a bronze badge to say I'm one of the good guys.
你懂我想表达的意思吗？
You know what I'm trying to say?
我告诉你我要怎么做
I'll tell you What I'll do.
休假几星期怎样？
Take off a few weeks, huh?
长出满脸落腮胡
Grow yourself a beard.
懒散地招惹苍蝇 先考虑一下
Draw flies. Just think about it for a while.
假如你回来时依然有此意 我可以接受
If you still feel the same way when you come back, that's okay by me.
去吧
Go on.
我不会改变心意
I'm not gonna change my mind.
在我决定要跟着你一起辞职之前 快出去
Get out of here, before I decide to come with you, huh?
再见 老费 谢了
Bye, Fif. Thanks.
你会回来的 洛卡谭斯基
You'll be back, Rockatansky!
你上瘾了 麦克斯
You're hooked, Max…
你心知肚明
…and you know it!
我从来无法对你敞开心怀 洁西 聊我的感受
I've never been able to say things to you, Jess. About how I feel.
我一直指望你会了解
Guess I always counted on you understanding.
我还小的时候
When I was a kid…
我和爸爸经常久久的散步
…me and my father used to go for long walks.
我还记得我爱盯着他的鞋看
I remember staring down at his shoes.
那是特制鞋 褐色的
They were special shoes. Brown.
他总是把鞋擦得闪闪发亮
And he always kept them real shiny.
他很高大 总是迈开大步走
He was tall, and he used to take long strides.
我则在他身边
And there I'd be right alongside him…
试着跟上他的脚步
…just trying to keep up with him.
我想他从来不知道 我对他感到有多骄傲
I don't think he ever knew how proud I felt of him.
或是我能在他身边有多欣慰
Or how good it felt just to be there alongside him.
每当我回想到那时 我依然觉得…
Even now, when I think back on it, I still feel…
重点是 洁西…
The thing is, Jess…
我当时对他说不出口 但我现在能对你说
…I couldn't tell him about it then, but I can tell you about it now.
我不想等上十年才告诉你 我现在对你的感受
I don't wanna wait 10 years to tell you how I'm feeling about you right now.
（你撞烂车 我们修车）
你好
Hello?
- 看一下 - 我们刚刚车子爆胎了
- Get a load of that! - We had a blowout a while back.
严重 非常严重 引擎还好吧？
Raunchy, very raunchy. ls the motor okay?
对 引擎还好 至于这个轮胎…
Yeah, the motor's fine. Look, about this tire…
我自己不常修这种状况 除了从路上清除它们
Don't do much work on these myself, except to scrape them off the road.
- 好 看看这轮胎怎么了？- 马上解决
- Yeah. Hey, how about this tire, huh? - Have it fixed in no time.
我卖一组登禄普给你 便宜到不行
I can sell you a set of Dunlops for next to nothing.
- 不必 谢了 - 我不记得我怎么拿到那些货的
- No, thanks. - I can't remember where I got them…
但我还是拿到了 懂我的意思吗？
…but I got them, know what I mean?
不 你只要帮我把这个轮胎修好就行
No, we'll be all right just as soon as we get this fixed.
- 麦克斯 - 有
- Max? - Yeah?
听着
Listen…
小不点让我买冰淇淋给他吃
…Sproggo's talked me into buying him an ice cream, so…
所以我们待会儿见…
I think I'll see you later.
没问题 海滩附近有间店
Sure, there's a shop just down the beach.
他们会非常感激你们的光临
They'll appreciate the business.
好极了 谢谢
Sure, thanks.
草莓冰淇淋
Toodle pip.
拜
Bye.
开车出来兜风？这是开车到处走的好时节
You just trucking around? Good time for just trucking.
我也希望我能自己去兜风 你们往哪里走？往北？
Wish I could do a bit myself. Which way you heading? North?
也许吧
Uh, maybe.
看我发现了什么好吃的
Look what's turned up for Sunday dinner.
主菜加甜点
Main course and dessert.
我最喜欢的那种
My favorite kind…
女的
…female.
嗯
Mm.
小心他的舌头 亲爱的 我看过他把 自己眉毛舔干净
Watch the tongue, sweetheart. I've seen him lick his eyebrow clean.
你一定花了不少钱
You must've spent some loot.
就像那句名言 速度快慢只是钱多钱少的问题
Like the sign says, speed's just a question of money.
你想开到多快？
How fast do you wanna go?
- 麦克斯 快上车 - 怎么回事？
- Max, quick, get in. - What's wrong?
听我的就是 上车
Just take my word for it, get in!
- 轮胎怎么办？- 拜托 麦克斯
- What about the tire? - Please, Max!
等等 轮胎 老兄
Your tire, man!
嘿 大哥
Hey, fella!
你的轮胎
Watch your tire!
这些人真疯狂
Crazy people!
这个世界到处都是疯子
The world's full of crazy people.
那辆旅行车 来过这里吗？
That wagon, was it here?
对 带着小孩的一对
Sure, a couple with a kid.
- 他们是谁？- 我还帮他们补了轮胎
- Who are they? - I was just fixing their tire.
但他们不要轮胎就跑了 那也不算太差
They left their goddamn spare. Not a bad one either.
- 他们是谁？- 一对夫妻…
- Who are they? - A couple…
经过这里 说向北边走吧 也许是北边
…passing through. Said they were heading north. Maybe.
你要开车吗？
You want to drive the car? No?
你不能开了 到后面去
You'd rather play with the ball? Into the back.
来 坐过去
There you go.
我现在还清楚的记得那张脸 那表情看起来象刚吞掉一块砖头
I can still see his face now. Looked as if he'd just swallowed a brick.
你真是刻簿的老女人 对吧 老大？
What a mean old lady you are. Huh, Sproggy?
- 你说够了 老兄 - 我们的狗呢
- That's enough from you, mate! - The dog.
怎么回事？
What's the matter with you?
你发现什么问题？
What you got there, pal?
麦克斯
Max!
对 我也这么觉得
Yeah, yeah, that's the way I see it too.
嗯 啊哈 唔
Yep. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
对 当然 很高兴跟你谈 再见
Sure. It's been nice talking to you. Bye.
看来你同意他的话
Take it you agreed with him.
- 他们不担心 我就不担心 - 至于那个呢？
- If they're not worried, I'm not. - What about that?
我想那是遣失物品
I figure it's lost property.
假如没人认领 我建议忘了它
If no one makes a claim to it, I say we can forget it.
我觉得还不错 洁西
Sounds okay to me, Jess.
我不知道
Don't know.
如果齐基也这样说 相信我 不会有事的
If Ziggy says so, believe me, it's okay.
走吧 阿梅还在农场里等这你们呢
Now, May's expecting you up at the farm.
在那里什么烦恼都会被一扫而空 只有绿绿的青草和肥肥的奶牛
You'll have no more trouble up there. Just green grass and fat cows.
- 修得怎样？- 快完成了
- How are you doing? - Mm. I'm getting there.
我想你应该把那小玩意 连接到那装置
I reckon you ought to connect the doohickey to the gizmo.
你过来
Come here, you.
你敢用那双脏手碰我 我就把你分尸 不要
You touch me with those hands and I'll rip you apart. No!
不 看看它们
No, look at them!
- 不 - 告诉我 我想知道
- No! No! - You gonna give me a hug?
不 不
No, no…
阿梅跟我说在树丛附近有片小海滩
May told me about the little beach down by the trees.
- 嗯 - 你想不想来？
- Mm. - Do you want to come?
我很想
Love to…
可是我得修好风扇皮带 否则我们永远走不了
…except that I've gotta fix the fan belt, or we're never gonna get out of here.
好 泰山 我去给你拿些香蕉来
Okay, Tarzan, I'll bring you back some bananas.
啊 好
All right.
嘿
Hey!
洁西 如果你在那里遇到班诺 别理他
Jessie. If you meet Benno down there, don't let him bother you.
他只是个宝宝
He's only a baby.
当然 阿梅
Sure, May.
来这里
Here, boy.
洁西 等一下
Jessie, Jessie, wait a minute.
冷静 告诉我是怎么回事
Calm down, now, and tell me what's the matter.
非常 非常幼稚的行为
Very, very naughty.
- 你告诉我阿梅… - 阿梅
- Now you tell May what you… - May.
阿梅 你打给齐基
May, you go and call Ziggy. Call Ziggy…
跟他说尽快赶过来
…and tell him to get here as fast as he can.
为什么 怎么了？
Why, what's going on?
我想我们遏到一点帮派麻烦 没事的
I think we've got some biker trouble. It's gonna be all right.
来吧 亲爱的 来 洁西 我们进屋里 来吧
Come on, darling. Come on, Jessie. Well, let's go into the house.
不会有事的…
It's gonna be all right. It's gonna be all right.
你过得很不顺心 亲爱的
You've had an awful time, darling…
但是那已经结束了
…but it's all over now.
一切都会没事的
Everything's going to be all right.
我只是去打电话
I've just got to go and make a phone call…
然后我们好好喝杯热茶怎样？
…and then we'll have a nice hot cup of tea, huh?
帮我接齐基 快点好不好？
Get me Ziggy, and hurry it up, will you?
我是阿梅史维西
It's May Swaisey.
小不点 喔 糟了
Sprog? Oh, no.
小不点？
Sprog?
小不点
Sprog!
不得了
Well, well.
是我们的年轻妈妈
It's our little mother.
那个人是康迪里尼
That there is Cundalini…
康迫里尼想要拿回他的手
…and Cundalini wants his hand back.
我要我的宝宝
I… I want my baby.
不如这样
Tell you what…
我跟你交换
…I'll swap you.
- 求你了 把我的宝宝还我 - 洁西
- Please, give me my baby. - Jessie.
洁西…
Jessie, Jessie.
你真是一点幽默感也没有
You've not got a sense of humor.
不过你有一张漂亮的脸蛋儿 非常的漂亮
You've got a pretty face, though, awful pretty.
漂亮的要命
Yeah, awful pretty.
我想你长了漂亮脸蛋 不需要幽默感
I suppose you don't need a sense of humor with a pretty face.
不过唯一的问题 小姐
The only trouble is though, missy…
假如你…
…if you should…
失去了那张脸蛋
…lose the face…
拜托 别伤害我的宝宝
Please, don't hurt my baby.
- 你就一无所有 - 你想要我怎样？
- …you've got nothing! - What do you want from me?
- 别改变话题 - 不准动
- Don't change the subject. - Hold it!
- 停在原地 - 啊
- Right there! - Aah!
- 我讨厌枪 - 老婆婆
- I hate guns. - Old lady.
退后
Stand back!
- 不准靠近 - 女人
- Stay back! - Woman!
退后
Stay back!
有谁胆敢动一下…
Anyone so much as breathes…
我轰烂他们
…I'll cream them!
开门
Open that door.
你们所有人 进去
You get over there.
将宝宝放在地上
Put the baby on the ground.
洁西
Jessie!
去开车
Get the van.
- 有扇门 - 不要停 直接冲过去
- Gate! - Don't stop. Just go right through.
现在怎么办？
Now what?!
- 马达 - 你想说什么？
- The motor! - What are you trying to say?
我不知道 它熄火了
I don't know, it just died on me.
下车 快跑
No! Run!
噢
Oh.
不 洁西
No, Jessie!
上帝怜悯
Lord have mercy!
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think?
我是医生 不是算命的
I'm a doctor, not a fortuneteller.
内伤很严重？
This your subdural?
- 是啊 没办法 - 是不是有太多问题
- Yes, that's her. - Lot of problems, huh?
多处创伤 脾 肝 肺 连枷胸…
Multiple traumas, spleen, liver, lung, flail chest…
左股骨颈 肾功能衰竭
…left neck of femur, renal shutdown.
听起来像购物清单 她还救得回来吗？
Reads like a grocery list. She salvageable?
当然 她昨晚总算是恢复一些知觉了
Yeah, sure, we got all her signs back last night.
- 亲属？- 她丈夫
- Relatives? - The husband.
他们还有个孩子 不过在送到这里之前就死了
They lost the kid. DOA.
听着 跟他说她会没事 要他别担心
Listen, tell him she's going to be all right. Tell him not to worry.
如果他需要 我可以跟他谈谈
If he wants, I'll talk to him.
我想他不希望跟任何人谈
I don't think he wants to talk to anyone.
他整天像僵尸般站在那里
He's been standing there like a zombie all day.
布巴赞内提 是你吗？
Bubba Zanetti, is that you?
你想来骑车发泄？
You come for the scooter?
它要到今天下午才会好
She won't be ready until this afternoon.
修前叉时还是遇到了点麻烦
Still having trouble with the front forks.
整修它们麻烦死了
They're mothers to work with.
嘿
Hey!
你这混蛋 你以为你在搞什么？
You asshole! What the molly frock do you think you're doing?
我要和你谈谈斩脚趾的事
You and me are gonna talk about the Toecutter.
我从没听说过他
Never heard of him. Aah!
你吃错什么药？
What the Christ?
我想了解那刺青
I want to know about the Toecutter.
我只关心自己的事
I mind my own business, don't I?
否则他们会杀掉我
I mean, they'd kill me if I didn't.
我说出名字 你只要回答是或不是
I'll say the names and you say "yes" or "no."
- 夜骑士 - 是
- Nightrider. - Yeah.
- 斩脚趾 - 是
- The Toecutter. - Yeah.
- 布巴赞内提 - 是
- Bubba Zanetti. - Yes!
还有更多人？
There's more?
- 强尼 - 强尼小子？
- They took Johnny. - Johnny the Boy?
- 对 还有其他人 - 在哪里？
- Yeah. Some others. - Where?
在海滩那里 寻找燃油
Out at the beaches, looking for fuel.
他们会回来吗？
Are they coming back?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们骑着摩托车到处走
They got their bikes.
其他的我真的就不知道了
I don't know anymore.
（停 禁区）
我们在查询一辆
Locate black Pursuit Special.
黑色追缉专用车
Unauthorized use by a Main Force officer.
别再玩了 布巴
Quit toying, Bubba.
轻松点 我知道自己在干嘛
Easy. I know what I'm doing.
嗨
Hi.
老兄
Hey, man. This…
情况不像你看到的那样
This isn't what it looks, man.
我只是过来看看
You know, I… I just came down here to check it out, and…
这个人已经翘辫子了
…this guy has already been snuffed.
你救不回他
Nothing you could do for him.
脚踝
Ankle.
没关系
It's okay.
你在干嘛 老兄？
What are you doing, man?
小心我的脚踝 我的脚
Careful, my ankle! My foot, man!
听着 我跟那里发生的事 一点关系也没有
Hey, listen, I had nothing to do with anything going on back there, man.
听一下行不行？听我说…
Hey, listen, man, will you? Listen to me!
听我说 他们是一帮不要命的疯子
Will you listen to me? They were a hell of a crazy people back there, man.
很坏的人 我跟那一切没关系
Some kind of bad people. I'm not responsible for anything.
等等 你要干嘛？
Ow. What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
What are you doing, man?
你说什么？你想干嘛？
What do you say? What are you doing?
听着 我不是坏人
Hey, listen, I'm not a bad man.
我生病了 看到没？我生病了
I'm sick, see? Sick.
这叫什么病来着？
What do you call it?
精神病 人格分裂
Psychopathic, you know. Personality disorder.
法官是这么说的
The judge, man, he said so.
你不会伤害我吧？
You're not gonna hurt me, are you?
天啊 你不能杀了我
Jesus! You can't kill me!
不能因为偷别人靴子就杀我
Not for stealing a man's boots!
他已经死了 老天帮忙
He was dead, for chrissakes!
他不需要靴子了
He won't need them anymore!
你要干嘛？
What are you doing?
我想知道你要干嘛
I wanna know what you're doing.
手铐用的链子 是用高强度钢制造的
The chain in those handcuffs is high-tensile steel.
你需要十分钟才能用它锯断
It'd take you 1O minutes to hack through it with this.
现在 假如你运气好
Now, if you're lucky…
你能在五分钟内锯断脚踝 开始
…you could hack through your ankle in five minutes.
你疯了 老兄
You're mad, man!
你以为我看来很傻是不是？
You think I look silly, don't you?
别用这套对付我
Don't bring this on me, man.
拜托别这样对我
Don't do this to me!
老天救命 我是个病人
Please, sweet Jesus. I was sick!
拜托别这样惩罚我
Don't bring this on me, please!